COVER LETTER

I am Guru Powar completed B.E.(mechanical) from Amravati University having 61.34%. I am having 5 year 2 months experience in cutting tool industry and have good knowledge about HSS and carbide tools.

Since last 1 year 2 months I am working with Kubera Tools as an Technical production Manager . Completed one day's training of ANCA (GX7) and ANCA Fast grind in Essen Carbide Tools, Completed Three day's training of ANCA (FX5) in Kubera tools .I am working on ANCA (TX7⁺), ANCA (GX7), ANCA(FX5), ANCA (MX5), ANCA Fast grind and also solving maintenance problem of machine and know about the Zoller smile400, Zoller smartcheck450 checking machine and having good knowledge of tool geometry .

I am ambitious to work. I am searching job in production as well as sales and application in tool industry.

Yours faithfully

Guru Powar

CURRICULUM VITAE

Guru Powar

Contact info.

Address : C/O Powar galli, AT/POST- Vadarage, TAL- Gadhinglaj

DIST- Kolhapur (M.H.)

Mobile No. : 9923447161, 8830942528 Email : powar.guru21@gmail.com

Personal Particulars

Age : 27 Years
Date of Birth : 4th Oct 1990
Nationality : Indian
Gender : Male

Academic Qualification

B.E. MECHANICAL From B.N.C.O.E. Pusad (MH) with Aggregate % marks 61.34%

SSC 2006 Kolhapur Board with 69.46%

HSC 2008 Kolhapur Board with 67.33%

Work Experience

Name of Employer: - AAYUDH TOOLS, AURANGABAD

Total Duration of work: - 17th Sep-2012 to 28th July-2014

Designation: - Trainee Production Engineer

Company Profile:- AAYUDH TOOLS, ISO certified company manufacturing various type of HSS and Carbide cutting tools .The company provides cutting tools to Bajaj auto ltd., TATA Motors, Mahindra and local companies in Aurangabad.

Name of Current Employer: - UTTAM TOOLS, PUNE

Total Duration of work: - 1stAug-2014 to 5thJAN-2016

Designation: - CNC Grinding Operator

Company Profile:- UTTAM TOOLS is a manufacturing and regrinding a various type of HSS, PCD and Carbide cutting tools. The company provides cutting tools to Bajaj auto, Shrinivas engg, Mahindra ltd and local companies in pune.

Company Training: Completed One day's training of ANCA(GX7) machine.

Name of Current Employer: - ESSEN CARBIDE, BANGALORE

Total Duration of work: - 10th jan-2016 to 15th sept-2016

Designation: - CNC Grinding Incharge

Company Profile:- ESSEN CARBIDE is a manufacturing and regrinding Carbide cutting tools. The company provides cutting tools to Sansera ltd, Maini ltd, and local companies in Bangalore.

Company Training:- Completed One day's training of ANCA(GX7)and ANCA Fast grind machine .

Name of Current Employer: - KUBERA TOOLS, PUNE

Total Duration of work: - 1st oct-2016 to Till date.

Designation: - Technical production Manager

Company Profile: - KUBERA TOOLS is a manufacturing various type of HSS, brazed tools, Carbide cutting tools and carbide tip tools. The company provides cutting tools to Bajaj auto, Bharat Forge, Mahindra ltd, Cummins India ltd, and local companies in pune

Company Training: Completed Three day's training of ANCA(FX5).

Job Profile & Responsibilities

Working on ANCA(TX7⁺), ANCA(MX5), ANCA(GX7),ANCA Fast grind machine, Zoller smile(400),zoller smartcheck(450), Blickle (multcheckpc500) and dressing(WENDT) machines to produce various types of drills, end mills, hole mills, reamers, slitting cutter, form tools and ball nose All type of HSS, carbide tip tools and Carbide tool.

- Selection of various types of material for cutting tools.
- To Monitor the complete process flow(from raw material to finish tool)

- To coordinate with inter department at all the stages such as Marketing, PPC, CRM, Quality assurance, Store.
- New tool development.
- Taking the trails on tools and give complete solution to customer.
- To make the quotation of tools.
- To achieve the sales Target.
- Awar of installation and maintenance of ANCA machine.
- Having knowledge of diamond wheel pack and their right use of operations.
- Aware of the manual BFW milling machine and HMT tool cutter machine.
- Maintain daily production records and process check sheet.
- Maintain corrective action plan against production losses.
- Maintain breakdown record of cutting tool and their FAR.
- Control production losses.
- Maintain quality of production.
- Monitor and achieve department objective.
- Making the special geometry tools as per customer needs.

Objective

To give best in myself to growth of enterprise to which I join and to explore my maximum working potential in a leading Industry.

Key skills

Skills : AutoCAD, Ms office

Strength: Leadership, Ambitious, Courageous, Dedicated to work

Hobbies : Playing Football and Listening Music

Language Known: English, Hindi and Marathi

Salary Detail

Current Salary : CTC: 5.72 L.p.a.

Expected salary : CTC: 7.2 L.p.a.

Location Preference : Any Where

Declaration

I hereby declaration that the above-mentioned information is correct up to my belief and knowledge and I bear the responsibility of the correctness of the above-mentioned particulars

PL	AC	E:-
----	----	-----

DATE:-

Guru Powar